My head is overflowing with thoughts
I can't allow anyone to know about
I've strayed into a world void of even mistakes
It's being rubbed in so deep it's hard to believe
This "world" that holds
only what the eye can see
Can I flush out the truth?
Plastic Tac Tic,
no one can go crazy anymore
You, too, are in a plastic beautiful world
In a world with too much beauty,
for some reason I can't see the light
My bursting heart is an eternal reflection
くそっ!
Shit!
Secret remains for you
Don't expose these false colors and futures
fake's plastic world
keep it secret motion
You fought quite well,
considering your wounds.
その傷で　よくやるもんだ
They must've realized it the
moment they saw each other.
きっと彼らは 一目見て分かったはずだ
２人は初めて出会うより　以前から…
That long before they had ever met,
ああなる運命だったんだろう
this destiny awaited them.
They were not like ships passing in the night.
すれ違っていたわけでもない
They understood each
other better than anyone else,
彼らは誰よりも深く　お互いを理解し
and each was focused solely on the other.
相手のことだけを　見詰めていた
お前は狡噛慎也だ
You are Shinya Kogami.
You are Shogo Makishima!
お前は槙島聖護だ
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:草泥马 知音   校对:西西   后期:时末
#01 Crime Coefficient
This is the Criminal Investigation Department,
part of the Public Safety Bureau.
Access to this block is
currently restricted to ensure safety.
こちらは公安局刑事課です
現在　この区画は安全のために立ち入りが制限されています
Neighborhood residents are
expected to evacuate immediately.
I repeat.
繰り返しお伝えします
近隣住民の皆さんは速やかに退去してください
こちらは公安局刑事課です
This is the Criminal Investigation Department,
part of the Public Safety Bureau.
Access to this block is
currently restricted to ensure safety.
現在　この区画は安全のために立ち入りが制限されています
す　すいません
- I-I'm sorry!
- Neighborhood residents are
expected to evacuate immediately.
- I-I'm sorry!
"Inspector: Akane Tsunemori"
Excuse me! Are you Inspector Ginoza?!
あの 監視官の宜野座さんでしょうか
That's me.
俺だ
What bad luck that you have to deal
with an incident right after you got posted.
配属早々に事件とは災難だったな
I'm Akane Tsunemori.
I've been assigned to the CID as of today!
本日付けで刑事課に配属になりました常守朱です
- Pleased to meet...
どうぞ　よろしく
- Sorry, but the CID is very short on manpower.
- Pleased to meet...
悪いが 刑事課の人手不足は深刻でね
新米扱いはしていられない
So I can't treat you like a newbie.
Our target is Nobuo Okura.
対象は大倉信夫
A street scanner flagged
him while doing a Hue Check,
街頭スキャナーで色相チェックに引っ掛かり
so a Security Drone ordered him to
receive therapy, but he refused and ran.
セキュリティードローンがセラピーを要求したが
拒絶して逃亡
The Psycho-Pass it recorded
for him was forest green.
記録したサイコパスはフォレストグリーン
His aggression and compulsion
are expected to be high.
高い攻撃性と強迫観念が予想される
To think that he didn't receive
treatment and let his Hue get so cloudy...
そんなに色相が濁るまで治療を受けなかったなんて
There's also a possibility
that he used incompatible drugs.
不適合薬物に手を出した可能性もある
In any case, he's a latent criminal,
何にせよ　シビュラ判定を待つまでもない潜在犯だ
one far enough gone that we
don't need to wait for Sibyl's Judgment.
The hassle is that the
place Okura ran to... is this block.
厄介なのは　大倉が逃げ込んだ
このブロックだ
Since this is an abolition block,
there's no relay device,
廃棄区画で中継器がないため
so Drones can't come in.
ドローンが進入できない
In addition...
それと 逃亡の途中で大倉は
I heard Okura abducted a
passerby and is holding her hostage.
通行人を拉致して人質にしているらしい
A hostage?!
人質が!?
According to a witness, it's a young woman.
目撃者の証言によれば若い女性だそうだ
We still haven't been
able to confirm her identity yet.
身元の確認はまだ取れていない
What about the residents' evacuation?
住民の退去は
Records state that this is an uninhabited block,
登録上は無人区画だが
but because of that,
it's become a den of homeless people.
おかげで浮浪者の巣窟だ
Be prepared.
覚悟しておけ
A paddy wagon!
護送車…
Don't think that the guys you're
about to meet are humans like us.
これから会う連中を
同じ人間と思うな
Their Psycho-Pass Crime Coefficients
exceeded the regulation value.
やつらはサイコパスの犯罪係数が規定値を超えた
They are people of bankrupt character.
人格破綻者だ
Normally, they would be completely
isolated as latent criminals.
本来ならば　潜在犯として隔離されるべきところを
However, they're allowed into
the outside world for the sole purpose
ただ一つ許可された社会活動として
同じ犯罪者を駆り立てる役目を与えられた
of flushing out criminals
just like themselves.
They're hunting dogs.
They're beasts used to hunt beasts.
やつらは猟犬
獣を狩るための獣だ
They're what we call "Enforcers."
They'll be your subordinates.
それが執行官 君が預かる部下たちだ
Is that cutie the newbie that people
have been talking about, Gino?
そっちのかわい子ちゃんが噂の新入りさんっすか
ギノさん
This is Inspector Akane Tsunemori.
常守朱監視官だ
From today on, she's your second owner.
今日から貴様らにとって ２人目の飼い主になる
P-Pleased to meet you!
よ　よろしくお願いします!
You guys all looked
through the target's data, right?
全員　対象のデータには目を通してあるな
We're gonna tighten
the noose on the cornered rat.
今から袋のねずみをさらに締めつぶす
We'll divide into two groups and take turns.
二手に分かれて順繰りに行く
Kunizuka and Kagari, come with me.
六合塚と縢は俺と来い
The other two...
あとの２人は
...accompany Inspector Tsunemori.
常守監視官に同伴しろ
- Roger.
了解
- What?! I wanna go with the cutie!
- Roger.
俺はかわい子ちゃんと一緒がいいっす
Geez, no comeback?
Seriously, he's unbelievable.
ゲッ　ツッコミなしとかマジありえねえ
It wasn't funny, that's why.
スベってるのよ
Later!
まったね
Well... uhm... What should I do?
えっと　あの　どうすれば
You could order us to stand by.
We wouldn't have any problems with that.
あんたが待機を命令してくれれば
それで何の問題もないんだが
You oughta earn your paycheck, pops.
給料泥棒はやめときな とっつあん。
Well, don't get so nervous, missy.
まあ そう緊張しなさんな　お嬢さん
You know how to use a Dominator, right?
ドミネーターの扱いは分かるよな
I-I did receive training on it, more or less...
い　一応研修は
This is a gun that reads the
Psycho-Pass of the target you're aiming at.
こいつは狙った相手のサイコパスを読み取る銃だ
Its safety is released only
when the target is a latent criminal.
相手が潜在犯だった場合のみセーフティーが解除される
You can just do what the Dominator
tells you. If it says shoot, then just shoot.
全部ドミネーターの言いなりになって
撃てと言われた相手を撃ちゃいい
"Just shoot"?
撃てばいいって
基本モードならパラライザーだ
If it's set to basic mode, it'll use Paralyzer.
It'll only paralyze the target,
撃たれても動けなくなるだけだから
so we'll take them into
custody and that'll be case closed.
それで身柄確保して一件落着
何　難しく考えることはない
Well, you don't have to take it too seriously.
Dominator Portable Psychological
Diagnosis and Suppression System
「携帯型心理診断」
「鎮圧執行システム ドミネーター起動しました」
has been activated.
User authentication,
Inspector Akane Tsunemori.
「ユーザー認証　常守朱監視官」
Affiliation: Public Safety Bureau,
Criminal Investigation Department.
「公安局刑事課所属 使用許諾確認」
Dominator usage approval confirmed.
You are a valid user.
「適正ユーザーです」
Oh that...
あ～ それな　志向性音声だから
- Current enforcement
mode is Non-Lethal Paralyzer.
- It's a directional voice, so only
you can hear it since you're holding it.
- Current enforcement
mode is Non-Lethal Paralyzer.
握ってるあんたにしか聞こえんよ
- Don't worry about it.
- Aim calmly and disable the target.
気にするな 最初は小うるさいだろうが
- It might be annoying at first,
but you'll get used to it soon.
- Aim calmly and disable the target.
そのうち慣れる
What about briefing?
ブリーフィングは
Aren't we going to have
a meeting to discuss a plan?
段取りの打ち合わせとかしないんでしょうか
We'll hunt the prey and you'll observe.
That's all there is to it.
俺たちが獲物を狩り あんたが見届ける
それだけのことだ
Uhm, a bit more in detail...
いや　もうちょっと具体的に
Well, he's saying, leave it to us.
まあ　任せとけってことだ
We may not look it, but we're experts, so...
俺たちも こう見えても専門家だからな
We have our own way of doing things.
俺たちには俺たちの流儀がある
But the one who's responsible
for our actions is you, the Inspector.
だが　その責任を負うのは監視官であるあんただ
So when you don't like how
I do things, use that and shoot me.
だから俺のやり口が気に入らないときは
そいつで俺を撃て
Wha...
なっ
We're latent criminals, too, just like the target.
俺たちも対象と同じ潜在犯だ
The Dominator will work on us, too.
ドミネーターは作動する
Oh, we haven't introduced ourselves yet.
あ～紹介が遅れたな
That stubborn fool is Shinya Kogami.
あのとうへんぼくは狡噛慎也
And, I'm Tomomi Masaoka. I look
forward to working with you, missy.
でもって　俺は征陸智己
よろしく頼むよ　お嬢さん
Y-Yes...
は　はあ
Well then, shall we go?
さて　じゃあ　行くかね
Up until today, I've lived a
more earnest life than anyone.
俺はな　今日まで誰よりも真面目にやってきた
誰も怒らせないように誰の迷惑にもならないように
All my life, I've been
walking on thin ice, trying my best
so that I wouldn't upset
anyone or be a bother to anyone.
おびえてビクビクしながら精いっぱいやってきた
And yet, a detector finds a problem
on me just once, and boom!
なのに　たった１回検知器に引っ掛かっただけで
They already treat me like I'm a criminal.
もう犯罪者扱いだ
This is it for me. Now that
it's come to this, it's all over.
もうおしまいだ こうなっちまったら最後
Employment, marriage...
They're impossible now.
就職も結婚も望みなんか　ありゃしねえ
Well, fine then.
I've restrained myself all this time.
だったらいいさ
これまで我慢してきた分好き放題にやってやる
So now, I'll just do whatever
I want. I'll take whatever I want!
欲しい物はぶん取る
I'll kill anyone I don't like!
気に入らねえやつはぶち殺す
P-Please don't.
や　やめて
I've always wanted...
あんたみてえなカワイイ女
...to have sex with a pretty
woman like you at least once...
一度でいいから 抱いてみたいと思ってたのさ
with a real, flesh-and-blood
woman, not a virtual one.
バーチャルじゃねえ 本物の肉の女をな
I wonder where Mr. Kogami went.
狡噛さん どこ行っちゃったんでしょう
Crime Coefficient is under 60.
「犯罪係数　アンダー６０」
Not a target for enforcement action.
「執行対象ではありません」
Trigger will be locked.
「トリガーをロックします」
Crime Coefficient is over 120.
「犯罪係数　オーバー１２０」
An Enforcer registered at
the Criminal Investigation Department.
「刑事課登録執行官 任意執行対象です」
He is an Enforce At Will target.
Safety will be released.
「セーフティーを解除します」
So he really is a latent criminal, too...
本当に潜在犯なんだ　この人も
despite the fact that he sounded pretty normal.
あんなに普通にしゃべってたのに
I've heard rumors about you.
お嬢ちゃんの噂は聞いてるぜ
I hear that you were the top
student at the training school.
訓練所じゃ 首席だったそうじゃないか
Well, kinda...
ええ　まあ
I'll give you a piece of friendly advice.
老婆心で言っとくが
You should forget about
everything you learned there.
あそこで教わったことは全部忘れた方がいい
None of that stuff is helpful
when you actually work on a case.
現場じゃ　何の役にも立たんよ
You think that's unreasonable?
理不尽だと思うかい
But you know, our work is made up
of unreasonable things in the first place.
ところがな
そもそも俺たちの仕事ってのは理不尽の塊なんだ
What a person thinks, or what they wish for...
誰が何を思い　何を願うのか
We live in a time where
everything in a person's mind
人の心の全てが機械で見通せる時代だってのに
can be made transparent by machines,
and yet, there are tons of people who'd
detest, deceive, or try to hurt others.
それでも　誰かを憎んだりだましたり
傷つけようとする連中がわんさといる
If that's not "unreasonable,"
what else would you call it?
これが理不尽じゃなくて何なんだ？
Everything you've been taught is
based on theories and logic.
あんたが教わってきた事柄は全て
理詰めのセオリーだ
Soon, you'll likely come to
realize how pointless they are.
それがどれだけ無意味なもんか
すぐに思い知る羽目になるだろうさ
Well, at least be prepared.
まあ　覚悟だけはしておくんだな
I...
私は
This is Hound 4.
こちらハウンド４
I found the target on the 4th floor
of the KT Building. What are your orders?
ＫＴビル４階で対象を発見 どうします
Okay, stay there and keep an eye on him.
よし　そのまま目を離すな
ハウンド２と俺が包囲する
Hound 2 and I will box him in.
Okay.
うん
But considering how worked up he is,
でも やっこさんのテンパり具合だと
the hostage girl may be at the end of her rope.
人質の子が限界っぽいっすよ
Shall I go in by myself and capture him?
俺一人で確保行っちゃいます
よし　しくじるなよ
Okay. Don't mess it up.
Roger.
了解
Crime Coefficient is over 190.
He is a target for enforcement action.
「犯罪係数　オーバー１９０」
「執行対象です」
- Safety will be released.
おやおや　悪い子だ
- My, my... What a bad boy.
- Safety will be released.
Kagari! What're you doing?!
縢　何をやっている
The Paralyzer isn't working!
パラライザーが効かねえ
野郎　興奮剤か何かキメてやがる
He's on stimulants or something!
「対象の脅威判定が更新されました」
Target's Threat Judgment has been updated.
Enforcement mode is Lethal Eliminator.
「執行モード リーサル·エリミネーター」
Shit!
くそっ!
Oh my...
Th-This is...
こ　これって
An Oracle by the Sibyl System.
シビュラシステムのご託宣だ
It says that Nobuo Okura is no longer
someone who's needed in this world.
大倉信夫はもうこの世にいらない人間なんだとさ
Oh no... Just because he
was detected by a street scanner...
そんな　ただ街頭スキャナーに検知されただけなのに
He probably drove himself into a corner.
自分で自分を追い込んじまったんだろうな
Nothing, including therapy,
will work on him anymore.
いまさらセラピーも何も通用しない
更生の余地なし
The judgment on him is that
there's no room for rehabilitation.
そう判定されちまったんだ
初陣で嫌な事件に当たっちまったな　お嬢ちゃん
It's unfortunate that your first
case is an unpleasant one, missy.
My Psycho-Pass has become this cloudy.
俺のサイコパス こんなに濁っちまってよ
もう泥みてえじゃねえか
Now it looks like mud.
Hey, your Psycho-Pass
looks exactly like mine now.
おい　あんたのサイコパスも
もう俺のとそっくりじゃねえか
- No...
- You and I are alike. If they catch
you, it'll be all over for you, too.
- No...
てめえも俺と同類だ
やつらに捕まったら終わりだ
死ぬまで一生潜在犯として拷問され続けるんだぜ
You'll be tortured by them as a
latent criminal for the rest of your life!
We'd better hurry up and settle
this or it'll be all over for the hostage girl.
とっとと片付けないと 人質の娘がヤバいことになる
Psycho-Hazard?
サイコハザード　ですか
Yeah. A Crime Coefficient can be contagious.
ああ 犯罪係数は伝染するからな
Young people these days
aren't tolerant against stress,
今どきの若いもんはストレスに耐性がないから
so they're easily affected
by violent urges and compulsions.
暴力衝動や強迫観念の影響を受けやすい
I wrote a thesis on that topic.
私　そのテーマで論文書きました
言っとくが　明日はわが身だぞ お嬢ちゃん
Let me tell you one thing, missy.
It could happen to any of us.
The reason we were made
Enforcers in the first place is...
そもそも俺たちが
何で執行官なんぞにされたのかと
Stop right there!
止まれ
Stay back!
来るな
Drop your guns!
銃を捨てろ
Step back!
下がれ
死ね
Die!
あっ　なっ 何だ　こりゃ
Wh-Wh-What the hell is this?!
My deepest sympathies.
ご愁傷さま
This is Hound 3. Enforcement completed.
ハウンド３ 執行完了
To think that you used an
old man and a newbie as a decoy...
年寄りと新米をおとりにするとは
You've sure got some big ones, don't you, Ko?
いい根性してんな
ええ　コウ
I was just earning my paycheck, pops.
給料分の仕事だろ　とっつあん
公安局です もう大丈夫　安心してください
We're with the Public Safety Bureau.
You're safe now. Please rest at ease.
落ち着いて あなたを助けに来たのよ
Calm down! We came to rescue you!
No... No... Don't... Don't...
嫌　やめて
やめて
Mr. Masaoka...
征陸さん
Missy...
お嬢ちゃん
...check her on your gun.
銃で確かめてみろ
「犯罪係数　オーバー１６０」
Crime Coefficient is over 160.
She is a target for enforcement action.
「執行対象です」
まあ　仕方ないわな
Well, I guess it can't be helped.
Stop it!
やめて
No! Nooooo!
嫌っ 嫌
What're you doing?!
何をする
あの人は　保護対象です
She needs to be taken
into protective custody!
That's exactly why Paralyzer exists!
そのためのパラライザーだろうが
We'll put her to sleep right
away and take her into custody!
今すぐ眠らせて確保するんだ
She's just confused!
You don't have to use violence on her!
彼女は混乱してるだけです
そんな乱暴なことしなくても
Listen. Dominators are Sibyl's eyes.
いいか ドミネーターはシビュラの目だ
This town's system itself
has decided that she's a threat!
この街のシステムそのものが彼女を脅威と判断したんだ
Think about what that means!
その意味を考えろ
So you'd shoot a victim
who hasn't committed a crime yet?!
だからって
何もしてない被害者を撃つなんてそんなの納得できません
I can't accept that!
Stay away... Don't come any closer.
来ないで もう近寄らないで
Stop it already...
もう　やめて
あっ　もう
I-I said stay away!
もう　もう　来んなよ!
狡噛さん
Mr. Kogami!
Please don't.
やめてください
Please!
お願いです
彼女は被害者で
She's the victim here and...
Target's Threat Judgment has been updated.
「対象の脅威判定が更新されました」
「執行モード リーサル·エリミネーター」
Enforcement mode is Lethal Eliminator.
Aim carefully and eliminate the target.
「慎重に照準を定め 対象を排除してください」
No...
そんな
Don't!
やめて
あっ　ああ
Stop it now. Throw that lighter away.
もうやめて
そのライターを捨てて
Or... this gun will kill you.
でないと この銃があなたを殺しちゃう
Please! I wanna help you!
お願い　あなたを助けたいの
So throw that lighter away.
だからライターを捨てて
Target's Threat Judgment has been updated.
「対象の脅威判定が更新されました」
Enforcement mode is Non-Lethal Paralyzer.
「執行モード ノンリーサル·パラライザー」
Aim calmly and bring the target under control.
「落ち着いて照準を定め 対象を制圧してください」
Inspector Tsunemori.
I'll expect you to thoroughly explain your
handling of this situation in the report.
Looks like the fairy tale
died a moment ago
This newbie we got sure is a piece of work...
In a hospital ward made of bricks,
I found it hard to sing
Red moon, come out on this foggy night
Now look at me, don't avert your gaze
I was born behind black iron bars
Wish for payback for the evil done
As you wish, I'll give you your justice
Before you destroy and get destroyed
Pay karma's price and have your revenge,
常守監視官 君の状況判断については
Monster without even a name
報告書できっちりと説明してもらう
Make the sky pour down black rain
I'm not wanted
こりゃ
I cracked and had a breakdown
とんでもない新人が来ちまったもんだな
To my beloved partners
in crime looking on
Now exhibit your justice
Treasuring those permanent scars
I'll accept this
body and go together with you,
Monster without a name